Harold S. Spencer Papers
Harold S. Spencer Papers
1888-1967
Spencer, Harold S.
43.0 linear ft.
Papers of the American theatrical agent. Collection includes index cards relating to work records of stage and motion picture actors and actresses (1920-1945); forty-five librettos printed before 1940; and clippings (1888-1964).
148680
Biographical History
Harold S. Spencer was an American theatrical agent in the mid-twentieth century.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Harold Spencer Papers consist of index cards, librettos, newsclippings, and miscellaneous material.
The Index Cards contain work and experience records of actors and actresses both in theatre and cinema. The years roughly span 1920-1945.
The Librettos comprise texts of 45 popular operas published before 1940.
The Newsclippings are the bulk of the collection. There are both folders arranged alphabetically and volumes arranged chronologically of clippings concerning entertainment stars from 1888-1964.
Miscellaneous contains various playscripts, graphic charts and one published play.
Arrangement of the Collection
All material is arranged alphabetically except for the volumes of news clippings, which are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
has the papers and records of many individuals and organizations related to dance, drama and theater. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Popular culture; Radio, television, film; Spencer, Harold S. -- Archives.; Actors -- United States.; Motion picture actors and actresses -- United States.; Theater -- United States.; Theatrical agents -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Librettos (documents for music); Theatrical agents.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Index cards
  - Actors
    - Deceased (Box 1)
    - Experience Records (Box 1)
    - Second (Box 2)
  - Actresses
    - Deceased (Box 2)
    - Experience Records (Box 3)
    - Second (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
  - Musicals (Box 4)
  - Plays (Box 4)
  - Playwrights (Box 5)
- Librettos
  - "Adrienne Lecourrer" (Box 5)
  - "Aida", 3 copies (Box 5)
  - "The Ameer" (Box 5)
  - "An Artist's Model" (Box 5)
  - "Il Barbiere de Siviglia" (Box 5)
  - "The Bartered Bride" (Box 5)
  - "La Boheme" (Box 5)
  - "Boris Godunoff" (Box 5)
  - "Cavalleria Rusticana" (Box 5)
  - "Don Giovanni" (Box 5)
  - "Don Pasquale" (Box 5)
  - "Fatinitza" (Box 5)
  - "Faust", 2 copies (Box 5)
  - "Fra Diavolo" (Box 5)
  - "Francesa Da Rimini" (Box 5)
  - "Genevieve de Brabert" (Box 5)
  - "La Gioconda" (Box 5)
  - "Les Huguenots" (Box 5)
  - "Lohengrin" (Box 5)
  - "Loveley" (Box 5)
  - "Louise" (Box 5)
  - "The Love Spell" (Box 5)
  - "Lucia di Lammermoor" (Box 5)
  - "Madame Butterfly", 2 copies (Box 5)
  - "Martha", 2 copies (Box 5)
  - "Die Meistersinger" (Box 5)
  - "Mignon" (Box 5)
  - "Norma", 2 copies (Box 5)
  - "Otello" (Box 5)
  - "I Pagliacci" (Box 5)
  - "Parsifal" (2 copies) (Box 5)
  - "Pelleas et Melisande" (Box 5)
  - "Rigoletto" (Box 5)
  - "Der Rosenkavlier" (Box 5)
  - "Samson and Dalilah" (Box 5)
  - "Siegfried" (Box 5)
  - "Tales of Hoffman" (Box 5)
  - "La Tosca" (Box 5)
  - "La Traviata" (Box 5)
  - "Tristan et Isolde" (Box 5)
  - "Il Trovatore", 3 copies (Box 5)
  - "Turandot" (Box 5)
  - "The Yeoman of the Guard" (Box 5)
- Newsclippings
  - Actors and Actresses
    - A, 10 folders (Box 5)
    - B, 18 folders (Box 6)
    - C, 18 folders (Box 6)
    - D, 14 folders (Box 6)
    - E, 5 folders (Box 7)
    - F, 11 folders (Box 7)
    - G, 14 folders (Box 7)
    - H, 18 folders (Box 7)
    - I, 4 folders (Box 7)
    - J, 4 folders (Box 7)
    - K, 7 folders (Box 8)
    - L, 14 folders (Box 8)
    - M, 23 folders (Box 8)
    - N, 7 folders (Box 8)
    - O, 5 folders (Box 8)
    - P, 13 folders (Box 9)
    - R, 13 folders (Box 9)
    - S, 17 folders (Box 9)
    - T, 6 folders (Box 9)
    - T, 7 folders (Box 10)
    - U-V, 8 folders (Box 10)
    - W, 17 folders (Box 10)
    - X,Y,Z, 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Operas A-Z, 16 folders (Box 10)
  - Volumes
    - 1888-1894 (Box 10)
    - 1894-1898, 2 volumes (Box 11)
    - Aug, 1898-Jun, 1899 (Box 11)
    - Sep, 1899-May, 1900 (Box 11)
    - Aug, 1900-Jun, 1901 (Box 11)
    - Aug, 1901-Jan, 1902 (Box 11)
    - Jan, 1902-May, 1902 (Box 12)
    - Aug, 1902-Feb, 1903 (Box 12)
    - May, 1903-Oct, 1904, 3 volumes (Box 12)
    - Oct, 1904-Jan, 1906, 6 volumes (Box 13)
    - Jan, 1906-Dec, 1906, 3 volumes (Box 14)
    - Mar, 1907-Dec, 1907, 2 volumes (Box 14)
    - Dec, 1907-Jun, 1909, 6 volumes (Box 15)
    - Jun, 1909-Nov, 1910, 6 volumes (Box 16)
    - Nov, 1910-Feb, 1912, 6 volumes (Box 17)
    - Feb, 1912-Oct, 1913, 6 volumes (Box 18)
    - Oct, 1913-Nov, 1915, 6 volumes (Box 19)
    - Nov, 1915-Oct, 1917, 6 volumes (Box 20)
    - Oct, 1917-May, 1919, 6 volumes (Box 21)
    - May, 1919-Feb, 1921, 6 volumes (Box 22)
    - Feb, 1921-Apr, 1923, 6 volumes (Box 23)
    - May, 1923-Nov, 1925, 6 volumes (Box 24)
    - Nov, 1925-Mar, 1928, 6 volumes (Box 25)
    - Mar, 1928-Jan, 1931, 6 volumes (Box 26)
    - Jan, 1931-Mar, 1934, 6 volumes (Box 27)
    - Mar, 1934-May, 1937, 6 volumes (Box 28)
    - May, 1937-Jul, 1940, 6 volumes (Box 29)
    - Jul, 1940-May, 1942, 5 volumes (Box 30)
    - May, 1942-Jan, 1944, 5 volumes (Box 31)
    - Jan, 1944-Oct, 1945, 4 volumes (Box 32)
    - Oct, 1945-Mar, 1947, 4 volumes (Box 33)
    - Mar, 1947-Oct, 1949, 5 volumes (Box 34)
    - Oct, 1949-Feb, 1952, 4 volumes (Box 35)
    - Feb, 1952-Nov, 1953, 4 volumes (Box 36)
    - Nov, 1953-Oct, 1955, 4 volumes (Box 37)
    - Oct, 1955-May, 1957, 4 volumes (Box 38)
    - May, 1957-Jul, 1959, 4 volumes (Box 39)
    - Jul, 1959-Nov, 1961, 4 volumes (Box 40)
    - Nov, 1961-Mar, 1964, 4 volumes (Box 41)
    - Mar, 1964-Apr, 1967, 4 volumes (Box 42)
    - Undated, 2 volumes (Box 43)
    - Undated, 3 volumes (Oversize 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Graphic Charts (Box 43)
  - Published play, The Tower of Nesle, Dumas (Box 43)
  - Scripts
    - Henry Irving, Ellen Terry, Portraits / E. Gordon Craig (Oversize 1)
    - Ladies in Retirement / Miller (Box 43)
    - The Male Animal / Miller (Box 43)
    - The Man Who Came to Dinner / Kaufman and Hart (Box 43)
    - The Play's the Thing / Wodehouse (Box 43)
    - Southern Exposure (Box 43)
    - Trifles / Glaspell (Box 43)
    - The Winslow Boy / Rattigan (Box 43)